D?
I never thought I'd be able to meet you!
"O-Oden"...
Is that my father's journal?!
It contains every detail about his grand life
and the world he experienced!
On that day, I found it at
the river below Oden Castle.
Someone in the castle
must have kept it from burning...
Lord Oden's...
Momonosuke!
He wrote a lot about you as well.
You were born on Whitebeard's ship, right?!
And then you went on to Roger's ship!
Mm-hmm.
Th-Though, since I was so young,
I do not remember much...
Whitebeard, Roger, and Oden...
They all said...
that twenty years in the future,
the New World was sure to be overrun
by young and powerful pirates!
That future is now!
I was sure that Ace would be
among them, leading the pack...
But when he died, I remembered
something from that night!
What...?
Crap!
I let it slip!
I wasn't supposed to say that!
You didn't hear that! Forget about it!
And don't you dare laugh either!
Sabo and I won't stand for it!
That's at the end...
of my kid brother's dream.
Sure, we laughed when Luffy
told us, but that's okay!
We're the only ones
who are allowed to laugh...
'cause we believe in him!
We really think he can do it, so–
Ace!
Huh?
Hey!
What's wrong, Yamato?
I won't laugh!
Those were the Pirate King's exact words!
The very words that stunned Oden!
In Kozuki Oden's journal, there was
a great man who said the same thing!
I'd never laugh at that!
Your brother is incredible!
A great man, huh?
Good to hear!
Maybe Luffy and I can grab
a drink with him someday!
I'm sure you guys would get along!
But he's already dead.
He is?!
Well, in that case, it'd be hard to see him...
It's done!
Oh?
This is your vivre card!
This is it?
It's just some paper.
Yeah! But this piece of paper will
bring us together again one day!
Give a piece to anyone you want
to keep track of or meet again.
Okay!
I'll be sure to do that.
Ace!
Yamato?!
We will meet again one day!
Ace!
You bet!
In reality...
that would be our final meeting.
I had no idea what was happening
in the outside world that day,
but I read about it in the newspaper later.
I learned that Ace was the son of
the Pirate King, Gol D. Roger...
and that his younger brother
had really made a name for himself!
That was the man you brought...
Luffy!
Momonosuke.
I return this to you, of course.
This is what Oden wrote about the future...
Twenty years from now,
a group of young and powerful pirates
shall start a new era in the New World!
If I die before then...
they will be the ones...
to strike down Kaido!
And here's another one...
How about you sit back
and watch how it's done?!
I refuse!
Same here!
So many heads ripe for the taking!
Straw Hat...
Linlin!
You wanna guess what this brat
said he'd be, right to my face?!
He sure is a cheeky one...
He talked a big game to me too!
He even destroyed my castle!
I believe you owe me an apology, Straw Hat!
Hey, punk...
Tell us again what you said you'll be...
Say it to right our faces!
You alright, Kin'emon?
I'm sorry...
I took too long.
I am... chagrined...
A-Alas...
when I pass on...
I will have nothing to show
Lord Oden but my shame!
Kin'e–
Would you carry...
Wano upon your back?!
I beg–
Dummy!
Of course I will!
It's my friends' country!
Hey, brat!
Sir...
Luffy...
We are all in...
your debt...
Traffy!
Send all of them downstairs!
Why is it shaking again?!
Luffy...
You call it haki, but in Wano
we refer to it as ryuo.
It means "to flow."
Lord Oden was executed!
By the shogun of Wano and the pirate Kaido!
Sir Raizo is safe!
We'd never sell out our friends!
=== We'd never sell out our friends! ===
Listen! You-gara must press on!
The neighborly man of Ebisu Town
is heading off to the great beyond!
The fires of rebellion...
Do they continue to burn?!
All ships, to Onigashima!
Charge!
On the day Kaido killed
Oden twenty years ago...
this country stopped moving forward!
No one deserves to be
laughed at when they die.
What's wrong with a stranger
defending this land?!
You say it! Aren't you an important person?!
You're the leader of these
great men, aren't you?!
I want to defeat Kaido!
Gum-Gum...
Red...
Roc!
Hey, Kaido! What are you doing?!
How the hell did he knock you down?!
I'm Monkey D. Luffy.
The man who's gonna surpass you both...
and become the King of the Pirates!
Wealth, fame, power...
Gold Roger, the King of the Pirates,
obtained everything the world has to offer.
What he said in his final moments
drove countless souls to the seas.
You want my treasure?
Go ahead.
Find it!
Everything is right where I left it!
People set their sights on the Grand Line
in pursuit of their dreams.
The world has truly entered
the Great Pirate Era!